# Yurii Kravchenko

Seattle, WA | <u>linktokway@gmail.com</u> | (425)-725-2293 | <u>LinkedIn</u> | <u>Website</u> Willing to relocate | Legally Authorized to Work in the US

### **SUMMARY**

Software Engineer with 3 years of experience in Software Development and 5 years of UI/UX and Web Design experience. Highly proficient with Javascript, React.js and Node.js. Built web products from scratch, including UI/UX design, development, and deployment. Proven collaboration with a team within Scrum/Agile environments. Constantly hungry to learn new and modern technologies to stay ahead of the curve, rapidly adapting to challenges and technologies, delivering high-quality solutions that not only meet but exceed expectations.

### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Programming Languages: JavaScript, TypeScript, Node.js

Libraries and Frameworks: React.js, Next.js, Three.js, jQuery, Handlebars.js, Tailwind, Bootstrap

CI/CD Tools: Git/Github, GitLab, GitHub Actions

Databases: SQL, My SQL

Other: NPM, REST APIs, HTML, CSS, SCSS/SASS/LESS, Ghost CLI(CMS), JSON, Gulp, Vite, JSX, Webpack, XML

**Operating Systems:** Linux, Windows **Methodologies:** Agile, Scrum, Kanban

**UX/UI:** Figma (Software) · Adobe Photoshop · Adobe Illustrator · Adobe After Effects · Adobe Premiere

### **EXPERIENCE**

DATAROB Remote
Software Engineer 2022 - Present

- Collaborated closely with the CEO to conduct a comprehensive audit of the main company website, identifying and resolving 30+ critical issues resulting in a 40% increase in website conversion rate.
- Redesigned the site, optimized the code, and increased client inquiries by 20-25%.
- Implemented Ghost CMS on Node.js, replacing outdated WordPress platform, resulting in 40% faster content moderation process and improved website performance.
- Elevated the PageSpeed Insights score from 47 to 99/100 score through code refactoring. Resulted in a seamless user experience, eliminating lags, loading issues, and enhancing overall website performance.
- Implemented a scalable article publishing feature, accommodating more than a few thousands of articles.
- Deployed an innovative content publication system by integrating ChatGPT, facilitating the production and dissemination of 600+ articles monthly.
- Integrated the cutting-edge approach that not only exceeded daily publication limits but also bolstered search engine visibility, increased website traffic, and achieved cost savings of \$100,000 per year in the marketing department.
- Developed Forka, a comprehensive client engagement resource providing insights into candidates, media, NFTs. Leveraged an Airtable database with 500+ top blockchain developers, investors, NFT creators, and media professionals, totaling over 3,000 records.

TROOM TROOM Hybrid

### Senior Graphic Design Specialist | UI/UX Designer

2020 - 2022

• Managed and accompanied teams in the process of forming and creating design for the YouTube channel with the auditory of 26M subscribers.

• Executed the integration of Scrum and Agile methodologies, resulting in a 30% decrease in project lead time and a 20% improvement in task prioritization and resource allocation.

CLICKABLE AGENCY Hybrid

# Web Designer | UI/UX Designer

2018 - 2020

• Created impactful graphic and promotional materials for leading bookmaker companies, driving a 20% increase in customer engagement and a 15% boost in conversion rates.

 Revitalized event landing pages by implementing innovative UI/UX practices, resulting in a 25% boost in user engagement. Created captivating interactive elements that expanded user satisfaction by 30% and reduced bounce rates by a notable 20%.

## **PROJECTS**

FORKA 2023

Skills: Javascript · React.js · Typescript · Node.js · HTML/CSS · Figma

HIRETOP 2023

HTTPS://HIRETOP.COM/

Skills: Javascript · Ghost CLI · React.js · Node.js · HTML/CSS · Figma

DATAROB 2022

https://datarob.com/

Skills: Javascript · Ghost CLI · React.js · Node.js · HTML/CSS · Figma

MOJAM | SKIN.CLUB + CSBRO 2022-2023

HTTPS://TOKWAY.GITHUB.IO/SKINCLUBMAJORPICK-EM/

Skills: React.js · Three.js · JavaScript · Figma · Tailwind · HTML/CSS

### **ACHIEVEMENTS**

GGI 2023 Ukraine Tales of Motanka	2023
CTCTL ZUZS UKRAINE LALES OF WIOTANKA	2023

https://globalgamejam.org/2023/games/tales-motanka-7-0

GGI 2022 Ukraine The best Unreal Engine Game 2022

https://globalgamejam.org/2022/games/test1-8

GGJ 2019 The best game according to the Community 2019

https://globalgamejam.org/2022/games/test1-8

### **EDUCATION**

# **O**DESA NATIONAL UNIVERSITY OF TECHNOLOGY

Odesa, Ukraine

Bachelor's Degree in Computer Engineering

2015-2021